Hamza Zulfigar

<u>hamzazulfiqar312@gmail.com</u>

in Hamza Zulfiqar | LinkedIn

(+92) 3410004135

HamzaZulfiqar312 (github.com)

Rawalpindi, Pakistan

PROFILE

Experienced software engineer with 2.5+ years in ASP.NET Core, Angular, MySQL/SQL. Versatile in both large and small teams, Agile methods, remote work, and project management tools (JIRA, TFS). Proactive, quick learner, pursuing professional growth while aligning with company values and goals.

EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Developer (Angular + .Net Core)

iii Mar 2023 - Present

NOBILITY | Islamabad, Pakistan

In Nobility, I worked on two projects NPM(Nobility Practice Management US-Medical Project), and HR Portal for managing employees records.

NPM (Nobility Practice Management)

- Devised and executed the application architecture for the NPM project in a team setting, utilizing Angular and ASP.NET
 Core to maximize scalability, maintainability, and performance.
- Successfully developed Reporting dashboard by working on Angular and .Net web API.
- Deployment of builds on different environments and fixing builds issues timely.
- Team management and fixing production issues timely.
- Engaged with project managers, product owners, and stakeholders to capture requirements and propose technical solutions, quaranteeing the timely delivery of the project.
- Responsible for managing code on git, and Release management.
- Led efforts to ensure faster and more efficient releases by collaborating with cross-functional teams and implementing continuous delivery practices
- Engaged with project managers, product owners, and stakeholders to capture requirements and propose technical solutions, guaranteeing the timely delivery of the project.
- Responsible for managing code on git, and Release management and configure the application environments, including development, staging, and production environments, ensuring seamless and accurate deployments.

HR Portal

- Contributed to the development and team management of development from scratch.
- Attend client meetings with BA for requirement gathering before development.
- Resources management for working on different modules.
- · Responsible of code quality management, release management and deployment on IIS server.

Skills: GitHub · ASP.NET Core · Angular · Scrum · Agile Methodologies SQL

Software Engineer

E Feb 2021 - Mar 2023

MTBC | Bagh AJK, Pakistan

- Contribute in the Development and maintenance of WEBSOFT, a cloud-based medical billing software that include key
 features like Claims management, Payment posting, Patient eligibility verification, Coding and billing, Denial management,
 Reporting, EHR, EOB, ERA.
- Developed billing reports through the use of ASP.NET Core, Angular, and SQL Server Procedures.
- Assumed responsibility for managing operations, including implementing hot fixes on the production environment during
 production hours to minimize downtime and ensure system stability.
- Contributed to development by implementing new features proposed by the business analyst to enhance WEBSOFT's functionality.
- Programmed and set up auto jobs to meet provider needs.

- Effectively communicated with cross-functional teams including Billing, Network, and QA teams to ensure timely delivery and high-quality output.
- Followed agile methodology, specifically Scrum, and utilized JIRA for project management and Git for version control.

Skills: GitHub · ASP.NET Core · Angular · Scrum · Agile Methodologies · Microsoft SQL Server

Account Manager

EDDEC 2018 - Feb 2021

MTBC | Bagh AJK, Pakistan

Worked for billing on different billing softwares.

- Worked as account manager for handling billing cycles, including accounts creation, charge entry, payment posting, denial management and insurance calls for AR follow-up.
- Responsible for creating billing reports and giving presentations to reps.

Skills: Medical billing, MS office

Android Developer - Interne

E Dec 2018 - Feb 2018

Signup Solution | Islamabad, Pakistan

- Served as an Android Development Intern, gaining hands-on experience in building mobile applications.
- Developed multiple applications, including a music player, calculator, and to-do list, using Android Studio and Java programming language.
- Gained knowledge of the software development life cycle
- Utilized MySQL and Firebase to create and manage CRUD (Create, Read, Update, Delete) functionalities for applications.

Skills: Android · Java · XML · Firebase · SQLite

EDUCATION

Bachelor' Degree

iii Oct 2014 - Dec 2018

UNIVERSITY OF POONCH | Pakistan

- Bachelor's Degree in computer science from "The University of Poonch Rawalakot" AJK
- Successfully completed the final year project on "Smart online physician" an android application which provide the health care facilities remotely.

SKILLS

LANGUAGES

- ASP.NET Core, ASP.NET
- Web API, Angular , JavaScript
- SQL Server (2008 2016)
- WordPress.
- JIRA
- Agile, SCRUM
- IIS
- Git, Azure

Urdu Urdu